<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on Joe Howarth</title>
    <link>https://joehowarth.github.io/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on Joe Howarth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>JosepheHowarth@gmail.com (Joe Howarth)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>JosepheHowarth@gmail.com (Joe Howarth)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joehowarth.github.io/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging A Player</title>
      <link>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/challengingtheplayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>JosepheHowarth@gmail.com (Joe Howarth)</author>
      <guid>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/challengingtheplayer/</guid>
      <description>How to challenge a Player Without extensive Reinforcement Learning, the AIs in the simulation cannot rival the long-term planning and strategic thinking of a thoughtful human. Most AI&amp;rsquo;s will be simple heuristic agents that respond to their environment in an attempt to maximize their particular objectives (reward function). These agents will be incapable of strategic thinking.
So how can the player be challenged in such an environment? Here are a few avenues:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Generation</title>
      <link>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/map-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 20:21:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>JosepheHowarth@gmail.com (Joe Howarth)</author>
      <guid>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/map-generation/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 in Historical Simulation series  Societies and peoples cannot exist without a world&amp;hellip; so let&amp;rsquo;s build one!
When starting this project, we could either use Earth as the source of geography and climate, or attempt to create plausible alternatives. Using Earth brings with it all the expectations from history about what should happen where and when, even if much of history was based not on inexorable drives, but chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Grand Strategy</title>
      <link>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/dynamic-grand-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 16:29:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>JosepheHowarth@gmail.com (Joe Howarth)</author>
      <guid>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/dynamic-grand-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Grand strategy games like Europa Universalis, Crusader Kings, Civilization, Victoria and even Total War each immerse the player in a simulated world. Which aspects of reality they focus on while abstracting (or ignoring) the rest, defines the experience and the game. Crusader Kings stands out as the only game attempting to model leaders&amp;rsquo; intricasy and humanity. Victoria, through representing and tying populations&amp;rsquo; plight or prosperity to events in the world abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing the Population System</title>
      <link>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/populationdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>JosepheHowarth@gmail.com (Joe Howarth)</author>
      <guid>https://joehowarth.github.io/posts/populationdesign/</guid>
      <description>Population Design Document How people are represented determines the flexibility, level of detail and performance of the above societal model. A vast number of attributes apply to people including: * health, age, sex * occupation, skills * culture, religion, race * ideas/mindsets/attitudes, (imperfect) information * relationships, membership of groups * location
For influential people (ie. actors), all these factors can be modelled on an individual basis, however this approach clearly can&amp;rsquo;t work for the nameless masses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>